JOEL SHEARON

CONTACT

9

Atlanta, GA 30305

((i))

7067294056

Y

vision2020joel@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Restful API
- Technical Writing
- Scrum
- Embedded Systems
 Development Software
- Technical Support
- Bug Fixes
- Programming
- Scripting Languages: PHP, Python, JavaScript
- Database Design
- Firmware Releases
- Performance and Scalability Optimization
- Customer Support

Persistent professional equipped with 8 years of comprehensive experience in the software engineering industry, coupled with a comprehensive background in electrical engineering from a top university. My happy place is the intersection of hardware and software and being at a place that challenges me and always strives for innovation and quality engineering.

WORK HISTORY

April 2022 - Current

Senior Software Engineer Workday, Atlanta, GA

- Developed key features for the financial settlements engine for Workday in Java and Workday internal languages. This system powers financial transactions for thousands of enterprise customers.
- Worked with program managers, developers, quality assurance engineers and direct customers to resolve technical issues in production tenants.
- Led efforts in development to improve both performance and user experience in our products.
- Tended to build server issues and automation pipelines.

October 2020 - April 2022

Software Engineer Microsoft, Atlanta, GA

- Worked on the Firmware Engineering team for Azure.
 Developed hotpatching for firmware, so security and performance updates could be made faster to the firmware without reboots being required on the servers.
- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Participated in architecture, design and implementation of back-end features using C, Python, and Windows batch scripting.
- Coordinated with other engineers to evaluate and improve software and hardware interfaces.

July 2016 - October 2020

Senior Support Engineer Microsoft, Charlotte, NC

- Developer Support for Azure customers. Assisted with customer code issues as they integrated their applications into Azure Cloud Storage. This involved code support for Java, .NET, Python, Javascript, etc. Additionally, support was for the SDKs offered by Microsoft.
- Implemented technical solutions to solve customer issues and increase satisfaction.
- Monitored systems in operation and quickly troubleshot errors. This included looking at server logs on a per tenant level for the distributed storage services.
- Documented technical issues and solutions to enable tracking history and maintain accurate logs.
- Led our team as a technical advisor and point of escalation for more technical and political customer issues.

EDUCATION

December 2021

Master of Science Computer Science Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

• 3.66 GPA

May 2016

Bachelor of Science Electrical Engineering Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

• 3.9 GPA